こいつが岩沢の代わりだと
She'll be filling in for Iwasawa?
ありえねー
You gotta be kidding me.
ゆいっていいます
I'm Yui! Glad to be working with you all!
よろしくお願いしま～す
だれこいつ
Who's she?
お前何も聞いてなかったのか
You weren't informed at all?
ガルデモのニュウボーカル候補だよ
She's GirlDeMo's new vocalist candidate.
You are aware that Girls Dead Monster is a rock band, correct?
いいですか　ガルズ　デッド　モンスターはロックバンドですよ
Is she planning on changing it into an idol group?
アイドルユニットにでもするつもりか
No, I'll sing it right!
おや　ちゃんと歌えますから
どうか聞いてから　判断してください
Please don't judge until after you've heard me!
At least she's got the look down.
形だけはサマになってるな
Day after day, I awake in a daze,
mezamete ha kurikaesu nemui asa ha
目覚めては繰り返す　眠い朝は
目覚めては繰り返す
眠い朝は
襟のタイをきつく締め
And fasten my collar tightly.
eri no tai wo kitsuku shime
襟のタイをきつく締め
教室のドアくぐると
As I walk through the door to my classroom,
kyoushitsu no doa kuguru to hon no sukoshi
教室のドアくぐるとほんの少し
ほんの少し胸を張って歩き出せる
I have the slightest bit of pride.
mune wo hatte arukidaseru
胸を張って歩き出せる
Then a wind rushed through that normal, everyday life.
sonna nichijou ni fukinukeru kaze
そんな日常に吹き抜ける風
そんな日常に
吹き抜ける風
I have a feeling I can hear it,
kikoeta ki ga shita
聞こえた気がした
聞こえた気がした　感じた気がしたんだ
I have a feeling I can sense it,
kanjita ki ga shitanda
感じた気がしたんだ
Beginning to tremble within my chest.
furuedasu ima kono mune de
震え出す今この胸で
震えだす 今この胸で
I have a feeling it's on its way,
mou kuru ki ga shita
もう来る気がした
As the millions of stars began to disappear,
ikuoku no hoshi ga kiesatteku no wo
幾億の星が消え去ってくのを
I sent them on their way,
miokutta
見送った
見送った 手を振った
Waving my hand,
te wo futta
手を振った
Whispering, "Congratulations".
yokatta ne, to
よかったね、と
良かったねと
Yay! Everyone,
や～　みんな　今日は来てくれてありがちょう
thank you for coming today!
ヤッホー
何かのパーフォーマンスですか
Is this some sort of performance?
翻譯 夏 今矢瘋
Is this death metal?
デスメタルだったのか
Crazy baby.
クレージーベビー
I-I'm dying-
し　死ぬ
特效 saber 時間&後期 月染不透
No, I think that was accidental...
い～や　事故のようだぞ
She's a pretty crazy girl.
とんでもないおてんば娘ね
萌月諸神聯合譯製
She's the complete opposite of the cool-beauty, Iwasawa-san.
クールビューティーだった岩沢さんとは正反対
I'm not too confident about having her on lead vocals for Girls Dead Monster.
ガルズデッドモンスターのリーダーボーカルとしてはいかがなものかと
別のものを探さないか
How about we find someone else?
そうするか～
I agree.
Hey!
こらぁ
ちゃんと歌えてただろ
I was singing it right, wasn't I?!
これでも岩沢さんの大ファンで
I'm a huge fan of Iwasawa-san, so I can sing all her songs!
全曲歌えるんだからな
But it wasn't really reaching people's hearts.
こころに訴えるもんがなかったか
ありませんね
Not in the least.
Nope.
ねえな
Damn it!
こらぁ！
Crushing a budding talent with poor senses of judgement like yours is just...!
そんな曖昧な感性で若い芽を摘み取りにかかるな
And you guys call yourselves upperclassmen?!
それでもお前ら先輩か
What a noisy girl.
うるさいヤツだな
There's also the fundamental issue of her attitude.
すでに言動に難有りだぞ
So what do we do?
どうするの
At least she's motivated.
やる気だけはありそうね
単にミーハーなだけだぜ
She's just a groupie.
Let's leave the judging up to the band members.
後はバンドメンバーに任せましょ
Really?!
本当ですか
Yay!
やった
I can pair up with Hisako-san, the guitarist!
ギターのひさ子さんと組めろ
Her godlike poses are totally awesome!
ひさ子さんのあの殺人的リフ捌き　たまんない～スよね
I wonder how her mind works?
あったまどうなってんスかね
I'd say she's fired.
首だな
首ですね
I'd say so, also.
なんか悪いこと言いましたか
Did I say something wrong?!
If the band's like this, we can't run any grand operations on Ball Day.
バンドがこんなんじゃ球技大会で大体的な作戦は行えないわね
"Ball Day"? There's such a thing?
球技大会
そんなものがあるのか
Of course there is, since it's a school.
そりゃあるわよ　普通の学校なんだから
So we'll sit and watch, eh?
大人しく見学か
We'll be participating, naturally.
もちろん参加するわよ
参加したら　消えてなくなるんじゃないのか
Won't we disappear, if we do?
We'll be participating as a guerilla force, of course.
もちろんゲリラ参加よ
Listen up, everyone. Each of you will gather people up and form a team.
いいあなた達　それぞれメンバーを集めてチームを作りなさい
Any team that loses to an NPC team...
一般生徒にも劣る成績を収めたチームには
...will face a punishment game more painful than death.
死よりも恐ろしい罰ゲームね
Don't ignore me!
こっちを無視すんな
I think she's just threatening us since we can't do anything about it.
何もできねえから　やけになってないか
Daily training is part of our duty.
日々の鍛錬も俺たちの役目
She's just enforcing it.
それのチェックさ
Otonashi.
音無
俺にはお前が必要だ
I need you.
これなのか
You're into that?
No way! I'm talking about the team!
ちげーよ　チームのことだよ
Let's team up, Otonashi.
組もうぜ　音無
負けたら　えらいことになる
We don't want to be losers in this.
ゆりっぺは本気だ
Yurippe is serious.
Do you know who else to get for the rest of the team?
で　ほかのメンバーの当てはあるのか
ふんふん　任せろ
Leave it to me.
I've basically survived here thanks to
my charisma so I'll form the best team.
人望で生き抜いてきたような人間だ　最強のチームを作ってやるぜ
あぁ　高松のチームに入っちゃったの
You joined Takamatsu's team?!
うん
Yeah.
訳わかんねえぜ
I don't get it! Why didn't you wait for me?
School Cafeteria
なんで待っててくんれねえの
あんたの誘いを待ってるほうがわけわかんないわよ
It makes less sense to wait for your invitation.
Besides, Takamatsu's better than you.
高松のほうがあんたより増しでしょ
She's got great athleticism, too.
あいつ運動神経拔群なのに
行った～
Damn.
Yeah, that's some great charisma there.
素晴らしい人望だな
仕方がない
Whatever, it'll be a dirty trick,
but let's have Matsushita Fifth join us,
even if he's more of a leader than a follower.
ちっとばかし卑怯だが　リーダー格の松下五段をメンバーに誘おう
I bet he's already taken.
もう取られてるだろ
No, he's waiting for me.
あいつは待っててくれてるよ
なんつーか　マブダチなんだ
He's, how shall I say... a true friend at heart.
Well, that was embarrassing...
照れるな
Oh, I already joined Takeyama's team.
ああ　それなら竹山のチームに入ったぞ
I had no reason to say no.
Behind the Gym
断る理由もなかったし　のう
ちょっと待ってぇ
Hold on just a minute!
Why?! I had faith in you!
何故だ
お前だけは信じてたのに
He said that he'd give me all the beef
udon lunch tickets he gets from now on.
いや　これから先肉うどんが当たった場合は
すべてまわしてくれるって言うから
Beef...
肉
He was saying, "A true friend at heart. Well, that was embarrassing..."
さっきこいつ
マブダチなんだ
照れるな
はは
って言ってたぞ
just a moment ago.
ばらすなよ
You don't have to repeat it!
Great.
く～そ
次はティーケーだ
We'll try T.K. next.
I'm counting on you, T.K.
ティーケー頼むぜ
ところでなぜみんなティーケーって言うんだ
By the way, why does everyone call him T.K.?
本人がティーケーつんったよ
He wants us to call him T.K.
本名は誰も知らねー　謎だらけなやつだ
No one knows his real name. He's a total mystery figure.
だが　俺もやつのことは信頼してる
But I trust him.
God damn!
ガッデム
You're acting like T.K., you know.
お前がティーケーみたいになってるからな
こ～の～
Behind
the Teachers' Building
By the way, what ball game are we playing?
お　の　そいや種目とか聞いてないんだけど
It's baseball.
野球だよ
So we need seven more people.
すると　メンバーは後七人
無理じゃねえ
I don't think that's possible.
Well, well. Look who's in it deep.
お困りのようですな
Oh, let's see. It's the suffocating death metal vocalist.
なんだ　悶絶パーフォーマンスのデスメタルボーカルか
んなパーフォーマンスにするキャラに見えるか
Do I even look like someone who'd do that kinda performance?!
見えるよ　十分
Yes, you do.
で　なんの用だよ
So, what do you want?
You're short on members, right?
メンバー足りないんでしょ
あたし戦力になるよ
I'm sure to add strength to your team.
戦力
"Strength"?
いや　待って
Hold on.
You could take a ball in the face and the opponent
pitcher would get booted for dangerous pitching style.
デッドボールを顔面で受けて危険球　相手ピッチャー退場
That works!
当た屋か
Welcome to the team!
よし　採用
Are you sure your brain didn't melt and drain out of your nose?
お前の脳みそ蕩けて鼻からこぼれ落ちてんじゃねえのか
くっおま　俺先輩だからな
Hey, remember, I'm your upperclassman!
Oh, excuse me then, upperclassman.
おっと　「先輩のお脳みそお蕩けになって
Did your cerebrum melt and seep out from your nostrils, perhaps?
お鼻からおこぼれになっておいで」では
なるか
As if!
先輩　痛いです
Senpai... that hurt!
It's the same for me, here!
俺だって　いてぇよ
But it does look like she has good athleticism.
でも　運動神経は良さそうだな
音無もなにいってんだよ
Snap out of it, Otonashi!
「こんな頭のネジの飛んだやつも仲間だ」なんて思われたくねえぜ
We don't want to be considered
friends with a girl who has a screw loose!
イタいです
That hurt...
Yeah, but all the people you had your eyes on are taken.
そんなこと言っても
目を付け　つった連中断れまくってるじゃないか
そ　そう
Yeah, totally! I was watching.
見てましたよ
なので　ゆいにゃん加勢しにやってきたわけです
That's why Yui-nyan is here to help you.
ん　もう一遍言ってみろ
Say that again.
Yui-nyan!
ゆいにゃん
そういうのが一番むかつくんだよ
Stuff like that pisses me off the most!
I give! I give! I give!
ギブ　ギブ　ギブ
Let's get a move on!
とっとと行くぞ
椎名っち～
Shiinacchi.
Where are you? Come out.
Gym Storage
どこだ　出て来いよ
Shiinacchi.
椎名っち～
何用だ
What brings you here?
We searched everywhere for you.
探したぜ
お前　運動神経いいじゃん
You've got great athleticism, right?
測ったこともない
I've never measured it.
I'm sure you're great.
絶対いけるって
野球　野球やろうぜ
Come play baseball with us.
あの日から
Back then...
I've been considering why I came up short compared to the new guy.
そこの新入りに遅れを取ってしまった理由をここでずっと考えていった
ギルド降下作戦の話しか
You mean when we did the Guild Operation Parachute?
確かに音無一人生き残ったのはありゃ伝説ものだよな
It really is something of a legendary act,
how Otonashi managed to survive until the end.
I was just lucky.
あれは運がよかっただけだ
すべての力において私はお前を遙かに凌いでいたはずだ
I should have been superior in all aspects.
I'm sure you are.
だろな
But I am inferior to you in one way... my concentration ability.
ただ一点劣っていたとすれば
それは集中力
No... I bet you have a better attention span than me.
いや～それもあんたのほうが遙かに上だろ
Ever since that day, I've been balancing this broom on my finger.
あの日以来　私はこの竹箒を指先の一点で支え続けている
アホですね
She's a dumbass, isn't she?
She is, but she's a valuable asset.
アホだが戦力だぜ
This is good timing.
いい頃間
勝負だ　小僧
I challenge you, kid.
Challenge me to what exactly, while balancing a broom like that?
ほうき立ててなんの勝負だよ
A baseball challenge, of course!
もちろん野球だよ
But make sure you two duke it out over scoring averages, got it?
勝負つってもちゃんと個人成績で勝負しろよ
No one-on-one matches!
一第一で戦うな
いいだろ
Very well.
I won't have to balance a broom, too, will I?
俺はほうき立てなくてもいいんだよな
Of course not. I'll show you the
difference in our concentration ability.
もちろん　集中力の歴然たる差　見せつけてやろ
All right, we're good.
よし　決まりだ
Got yourself another dumbass on the team!
アホばかり増えていきますね
So we've got four now...
これで四人かあ
I guess we'll have to ask him.
仕方ねえ　あいつを入れるか
No one would ask him to join the team.
あいつを誘うやつなんていねえ
Riverbed
Under the Second Bridge
He's impulsive and doesn't listen to
orders from anyone other than Yurippe.
直上的でゆりっぺ以外の指示には従わない
So he's pretty much another dumbass.
つまり　あの人もアホなんですね
だがアホは利用できる
But dumbasses are easy to use.
And look, no one's better at swinging around a long stick than he is.
しかも見ろ
長い棒振らせたら右に出るやつはいない
ふん　ついに来たか
So the time has come.
The time to settle our score!
決着の時がな
Whoa, let's test a few things out first.
ああ　だがまず　小手調べ
You'll have to show which of you is the better athlete.
球技大会でお前とこいつどちらの運動神経が上か　見せてもらおう
Why?
なぜ
強いだけじゃゆりっぺは振り向いてくれないぜ
Strength alone won't make Yurippe notice you.
Deal.
いいだろ
He really is a dumbass. He hasn't even realised he's being used.
アホだ
利用されてることに気付いていない
ごめんな
Sorry.
Rooftop
Classroom Building A
Looks like all the others are already taken by other teams.
ほとんど戦線メンバーが別のチームに取られてるな
We're still only five strong. What do you propose we do?
まだ五人だぞどうするつもりだ
Can't you do something about that broom?
そのほうきを下ろせないのか
真面目にしゃべってでもギャグにしか見えねえぞ
Even if you are serious, with that you look like you're playing around.
That only happens when my concentration is broken.
それは私の集中力が途切れたときだ
How's this, then?!
んじゃ　これでどうだ
What?!
な～にィ
What was that for?
何をする
おいおい　仲間割れするなよ
Hey now, quit fighting.
日向　お前なんとか
Hinata, why don't you-
Hinata?
日向
Hinata!
どうした
What's wrong?
Oh, it's nothing.
いや　なんでもねえ
ちょっとボーッとしちまった
I zoned out for a minute.
そうか
Well, what can we do?
仕様がねえな
後は一般生徒で賄うか
We'll recruit some normal NPCs.
Oh, yeah!
はい　はい
I'll bring over my good friends!
あたし　仲のいい友達連れてきますよ
友達
"Friends"?
あたし達　その
We're um...
ゆいにゃんさんのファンって言うか
Yui-nyansan's fans, I guess.
勝手に親衛隊っていうか
We're basically her self-proclaimed bodyguards.
Yui-nyan has been doing her own street lives without becoming arrogant about her talent.
ゆいにゃんは才能に驕ることなく
Hallway
Classroom Building C
地道にストリートライブとか積み重ねてきてますから
They're all groupies! Will they really be of any help?
ミーハー女ばっかりじゃねえかよ
こんなもん戦力になるかな
Still, even all combined, there's still only eight.
で　合わせても八人なわけだが
仕方ねえか
Who cares?
We have enough.
これだけ揃えば十分だろ
そもそもゲリラ参戦だ
We're playing this guerilla-style anyway.
We'll leave the centre fielder out, and have the
left and right fielder move toward the centre some.
センター抜きにして　ライトとレフトを中間よりに守らせれば十分さ
Are you sure?
いいのか　そんなんで
モエノツキカミガミ
Baseball Field
Ball Day, 1st Field
Home run!
ホームラン
Wow.
Way to go, T.K.!
さすがだぜ　ティーケー
It really is a total mystery what you were before you died!
死ぬまでなにやってたか　謎だらけだぜ
ドント　ストップ　キャッチ
Don't stop dancing!
Sports Field
Ball Day, 2nd Field
It's outta there!
いったぞフェア
Anti-Tenshi Operation HQ
Looks like the guerilla operation is going well.
ゲリラ作戦は順調な滑りだしね
I wonder how Tenshi-san likes this.
さて　天使さんのご気分はいかがかしら
我らが戦線チームはどこも順調に勝ち残ってますよ
All the Battlefront teams are moving up the ladder pretty well.
Shall we get a move on, too?
んじゃ　一丁俺らも行きますか
Another one...
またか
Nobody's team will be able to move up without beating us first.
この次に進めるのは俺たちのチームに勝ったほうってことで
How about rock paper scissors to decide the challenger?
じゃん拳で決めてくんれない
The number of teams just keep increasing.
どんどんチームが増えてきやがる
Come on. We're students of this school, too.
だって俺たちもこの学校の生徒だぜ
Hey, you plead, too.
ほら　お前もお願いしろよ
Let us play, damn it!
本気でこいや　こらぁ
関　関節が砕けます
What do you think you're doing, threatening him?
どす利かせてどうすんだ
My joints will get pulled out of place!
ホームランも打ってなくなります
I won't be able to hit a home run!
んな期待最初からしてねえよ
No one's expecting that out of you!
ここで負けたら罰ゲーム決定だからな
If we lose here, we're bound to face the punishment game.
We need to be pumped for this first game.
初戦は気合入れねぇと
一番　おまえなぁ
You're up to bat first.
Me?
俺かよ
What about me?!
俺はッ！
Calm down.
まあ　待って　で　二番は俺
I'll bat second.
Shiina's third.
椎名が三番
そして、四番がおまえだ
And you're batting fourth.
走者一掃しねぇと、てめぇ　の負けだからなぁ
If you don't bring everyone home, you lose.
いいだろう　容易いことだ
Very well. That's an easy task to accomplish.
Get seven runs in, and it'll be a cold game.
七点以上でコールドだ
Let's end this before Tenshi even gets here.
天使が来る前に片付けてちまおうぜ
よし　いくぞッ
Let's do this.
Fight!
ファイト（Fight）！！おおおぉーッ！！
Y-Yeah...
おっおーーおぉぉッ
What a striking lack of unity.
驚くべき団結力のなさだなぁ
Play ball!
プレーボール（play ball）
コールド狙いか
Trying to end it with a cold game, eh?
Then I'd better get on base.
つーことは先頭打者の俺が出ねぇと
Yay!
やったー
Nice going!
Is that the best you can do?!
貴様の打球はそんなものか
What did you say?!
なんだとッ
You can do better!
まだまだーッ！！
There's no sport like this!
そんな競技は存在しねえ
You're out!
アウト
They're dumbasses.
アホですね
ふん　まったく
Geez.
Such child's play.
遊びもいいとこだなぁ
Are you ready?
いいのか
For what?
なにが
Bring it!
こーい
Home run!
ホームラン
No way...
そんな
So, why am I the pitcher?
で　なぜ俺がピッチャーなんだ
Noda hit the home run,
野田にホームラン打たれたんだから
so now you'll have to keep their half of the innings at 0.
今度はおまえが零点に抑えて巻き返すしかないだろう
Who are we fighting against...?
俺たちは誰と戦っているんだ
Bring it on!
こーい
ストライク
Strike!
Is that all you've got?!
そんなものか
How's this?!
こッ　この
That's nothing!
まだまだ
You...!
野郎
やろう
Quit playing between yourselves!
だから二人だけでするな
I guess stupidity is terminal, even after death.
アホは死んでも治らないんですね
Foul ball!
Team
Team Hinata
Team Mori
Out!
アウト
Wow. Dumbass.
うわ　アホだ
Team
Team Hinata
Team Mori
Hinata Team: third inning, cold game victory.
日向チーム３回コールド勝ちです
Okay, the Battlefront teams are steadily making their way up.
よし、順当に戦線チームが勝ち上がってきてるわね
Everyone's seriously playing in fear of the punishment game more painful than death.
みんな死より恐ろしい罰ゲームとやらを恐れて　必死ねぇ
滑稽だわ
How hilarious.
Your dreadful punishment games are famous amongst the Battlefront members.
戦線ではゆりっぺさんの罰ゲームを受けた者は発狂し
人格が変わると有名ですから
You're right. Hey, wait! What sort of punishment games?!
そうね
ってどんな罰ゲームよ
I can't comment on it, since I've never experienced one.
いや　私は受けたことはありませんので
I've never done one, eith-
私だって　課したことなっ
Hold on.
おっと
Seems she was successfully lured to the field.
炙り出しに成功ね
こっちは武器もなし
They don't have weapons, just bats and gloves.
あるのはバットにグローブ
I wonder what kind of peaceful solution they'll try to come up with.
果たしてどんな平和的解決を求めるのかしら
Let's see what they do.
見ものだわ
Your team has not enrolled in the event.
あなた達のチームは参加登録していない
Who cares? It's meaningful that we take part in the event.
別にいいだろう
参加することに意義がある
生徒会副会長の直井です
I'm Naoi, the Student Council Vice President.
我々は生徒会チームを結成しました
We have formed a team for the Student Council.
あなた達が関わるチームは
We will properly eliminate the team you're a part of.
我々が正当の手段で排除していきます
なに　そっちはメンバー全員が野球部のレギュラーってわけ
Hey, now. A team composed of the
starting line-up of the baseball team?
ふんふん　いくらなんでも　勝てるわけねえじゃん
How do we stand a chance against this?
頭洗って　待っとけよなあ
Look forward to getting shoved up!
おまえは二三振だっただろうが
You keep your mouth shut!
もっと洗うのはみきだ
And it's "shot down"!
頭だったら衛生上の身嗜みだ
Do you need a bat "shoved up" your ass?!
That hurts!
い　痛いです
竹山チームに続き高松チーム
The Takamatsu team lost with a cold game in the second inning,
followed thereafter by the Takeyama team.
二回コールド負けです
God damn it!
クーッ　あんなの犯則じゃない
Oh, man! That's totally unfair!
残るのは１チームか
We only have one team left now. Which one was it again?
どこ
日向さんのチームです
It's Hinata-san's team.
クーッーー
天使にフェアにぎゃふんと言わせようとしていたのに
And here I wanted to make Tenshi cry, too.
まったく使えない連中ね
That useless bunch...
ついに来てやったぜ
So we're here.
では　これより決勝戦を始めます
We'll now start the final game.
チッ　かわいくねぇなあ
How uncute.
挑発の一つもしてみろってんだ
She should provoke us a little.
プレーボール（play ball）
Play ball!
ホームラン
Home run!
よっしゃあ
All right!
Student Council
Hinata
Student Coun
Student Cou
Student Co
Student C
Student
タイム
Time out!
やべえなあ
This sucks. We can't hold off the baseball regulars.
さすがに野球部のレギュラー相手じゃ押さえきれねぇ
特にうちの外野は笊だから
Especially our outfielders. They're completely useless.
Oh, I had an extra lunch ticket, so I gave it to him as a treat.
食券が余ってだから　奢ってやったんだ
おまえかよ
You did that for us?!
よしッ　よかった
Well done! He never forgets gratitude for food!
あいつは食い物の義理は忘れない
これで外野の守備もバッチシだぜ
Now we're set with the outfielders!
I give! I give! I give!
ギブギブ
後で殺す
I'll kill you later!
いいぞ松下五段
Great, Matsushita Fifth!
もう野球チームというより雑技団だなあ
This is more like a circus than a baseball game.
アウト
Out!
スリーアウト　　チェンジ
Three outs! Change!
よし
Yes!
ピッチャー交替よ
Change pitchers.
Hinata
Student Council
Team
こんな調子なら勝ってる
We could win at this rate!
やるじゃない　連中
They're doing pretty well.
こんなフェアによん
And playing so fair, too.
天使の思うままにならないことなんて　曾てあったかしら
Has anything ever gone so much against Tenshi's plans before?
いい気味ねぇ
Serves her right.
ゆりっぺさん　悪役のようですよ
Yurippe-san, you sound like a villain.
勝ってるかもしれない
We might be able to win.
最終回　一点差
Final innings. One run ahead.
ツーアウト　ランナー
Two outs, runners on second and third bases.
二三塁
タイム
Time out!
やべぇ　抑える自信がねえよ
Crap, I don't think I can hold him off.
なあ　ピッチャー換えてくるッ
Hey, could you switch pitchers-
どうした　日向
What's wrong, Hinata?
いや
Oh, nothing. A long time ago, when I was still alive, something similar to this happened.
昔生きた頃に似たようなことがあったけってなぁ
すげえ大事な試合だったんだ
It was a really important game.
おまえ　震えてるのか
Are you shivering?
えっ　そっか
Am I?
変だな
That's strange.
何があったんだ
What happened?
分かんねぇ
I don't know.
よく覚えてねんだ
I don't remember well.
俺　野球部でさ
I used to be on the baseball team.
甲子園目指しててさ
We were trying to go to the national Koushien finals.
死にそうに暑くて　口中泥の味しかしなくて
It was deadly hot.
All I could taste was dirt in my mouth.
そういうのは覚えてる
I remember those details.
最後の地方大会の最終回
It was during one of the regional game finals.
ツーアウトで　ランナーが二三塁にいてさ
There were two outs, runners on second and third bases.
簡単なセカンドフライが上がったんだ
A pop fly went to second base.
ほぼ定位置
Pretty much where I stood.
ただ　それを取れたのか　落としちまったのか
But...
I don't remember... if I caught that...
それだけは思い出せねんだ
...or not...
いや　取れてたんなら忘れるわけねぇよなぁ
Well, if I had, there's no way I would have forgotten it.
きっと　取れなかったんだ
I probably missed it.
掛ける声も見つからねえなあ
I can't find a damn thing to say to him.
皆の三年間の努力を
Yeah, since he went and wasted everyone's three years' worth of effort all by himself.
一人で無駄にしちまったんだからなぁ
強烈な疫病神だぜ
He's a total pest.
あんま言うなよ
Don't rub it in. He hasn't moved at all.
さっきから動いてねぇぜ　あいつ
立ち直れるのかなぁ
Think he'll recover?
俺　心配だから　ちっと先輩に相談しとくよ
I'm a little worried, so I'll go talk to the upperclassmen.
よう　話は聞いたぜ
Hey.
I heard the story.
大変だったなあ
Sorry man. Must've been tough, huh?
辛いだろう
そんなおまえに　今必要なのは
I bet something like this is what you need right now.
こういうのじゃないか
大丈夫
It's fine. I mean, just try it once. Give it a shot.
まあ　気軽に一回だけでいいから
試してみるよ
Okay? It'll help you relax.
なぁ　楽になれるぜ
おまえ　消えるのか
Are you... going to disappear?
おまえ　この試合に勝ったら　消えるのか
I mean... will you disappear if we win this game?
Me? Disappear? What are you saying?
消えねぇよ
なんで
こんなことで
I won't disappear because of something like this.
消えるかよ
決めろーッ　音無
Finish the game, Otonashi!
まさか　セカンドフライ
No way.
A second base pop fly.
あの時と同じだ
It's exactly the same as that day.
日向―ッ
Hinata!
こいつを取れば
If I catch this, will the game end?
終わるのか
そいつは最高に気持ちがいいなあ
That... would be the best feeling ever...
取るな　日向
Don't catch that, Hinata!
俺は　俺は　おまえに消えてほしくない
I-
I... don't want you to disappear!
隙あり
Gotcha!
よくも卍固めにしまくってるッ　これかなぁ
This is all for the locks you put me in!
このーーッ
Home in.
ホームイン
At a time like this...
（死ね 死ね）
この　こんな時に
What do you think you're doing?!
何にキレてんだよ
My bad! I'll wait for the right moment next time!
すみません　次はちゃんと頃合いをはかります
Tap out! I tap out!
ギブギブ
知るかッ！
Not happening!
Dammit! We lost after coming this far?!
Home in! Game set!
ホームイン
ゲームセット
I'll never forgive you for this!
てめぇ　今のだけは絶対に許さん
That hurts! I'm gonna pass out!
痛い痛い
Die! Die!
落ちる落ちる
I wish they'd both disappear...
死ね　死ね
二人ども消えてくれ
いつも一人で歩いてた
I've always walked this path alone; when I look back, everyone is so far away.
itsumo hitori de aruiteta furikaeru to minna ha tooku
いつもひとりで歩いてた　振り返るとみんなは遠く
振り返るとみんなは遠く
●
それでも私は歩いたそれが強さだった
Even so, I kept on walking. That was my strength.
soredemo atashi ha aruita sore ga tsuyosa datta
それでもあたしは歩いた　それが強さだった
．
●
もう何も 怖くない
"Nothing frightens me any longer", I mumble softly.
mou nanimo kowakunai sou tsubuyaitemiseru
もう何も恐くない　そう呟いてみせる
そうつぶやいてみせる
いつか　人は一人になって
．
Eventually, everyone ends up alone,
itsuka hito ha hitori ni natte
いつか人は一人になって
思い出の中に生きてくだけ
．
And is left with only their memories.
omoide no naka ni ikiteku dake
思い出の中に生きてくだけ
孤独さえ愛し笑ってられるように
．
In order to appreciate even sorrow and continue smiling,
kodoku sae aishi waratterareru you ni
孤独さえ愛し笑ってられるように
私は戦うんだ
I'll keep on fighting,
atashi ha tatakaunda
あたしは戦うんだ
涙なんて見せないんだ
I won't show you my tears.
namida nante misenainda
涙なんて見せないんだ
Next Episode Preview
Don't you know the test is starting?
I knew it'd come to me!
I resign!
What did you guys do?
The operation is nearly perfect.
What the hell is that?!
Look, I drew number one!
What do... we fight against...?
It's the final piece Iwasawa left behind.
It's a Physics test, you know...
I only need true love!
How ridiculous...
I even took such a small piece of happiness away from her...